我们关心的其中主要的事情
就是有个可靠的能源发生器
Reliable power generation is one
of our greatest concerns.
根据这个技术，我们希望很快就可以转换出来
With this project, we hope, soon, to be able to convert
利用我们从星体表层以下捕捉到的压缩热源
and utilize the intense heat trapped
beneath the surface of our planet.
也就是地热能
Geothermal energy.
什么，靠这个?!
What, using this?!
你知道地热能有多复杂么
Do you have any idea how complex geo-thermal...
McKay
McKay...
它会产生奇迹效应的
It's gonna work like a charm.
看起来，您有重要的事做, 长官
Looks like you're accomplishing
great things here, Chancellor.
自从上次幽灵出现
Since the last Wraith culling
我们一直在努力重建我们的家园
we have worked diligently to rebuild our society.
难道你不担心，你们所做的可能再次招来幽灵们的侵袭?
Are you not concerned that your efforts
will attract the attention of the Wraith?
我们也担心
Yes...
但我们不能因此停下发展的进度
but we refuse to let that stop us
from striving to reach our potential.
否则就意味着他们轻易获胜了
To do otherwise would simply mean victory for them.
无论如何，我们现在正致力于开发有效的防御系统
However, we currently are working on a viable defence.
防御系统?
Defence?
真的么?
Really?
我们在这里待了两天了，怎么从来没听你说过?
We've been here for two days before you mention that?
我必须先确定你是否可信
I had to learn that you could be trusted.
你是说某种防御武器?
You're talking about some sort of defensive weapon?
你可以这么说
You could call it that.
我们希望依靠这个抵抗下一次幽灵们的侵袭
Something that we hope will protect us
from the next Wraith culling.
你希望再来一次?
So you are expecting it to happen again?
当然
Of course.
如果像历史上那样，幽灵们再次侵袭,
But if the Wraith return as they have historically,
这件事情至少要到50年之后才会发生
they won't be here for at least another fifty years.
50年，你说的
Fifty years, you say.
那武器怎么样?
How about that weapon?
是的，是的，过来这边
Yes, yes if you'll just come this way.
你还没告诉他们，我们已经把那个幽灵给弄醒了吧?
You haven't told them that we practically
woke the Wraith from hibernation, have you?
嗯还没找到机会
Well... I really haven't had the chance
我们到这两天了!
We've been here two days!
实际上是，一天半
One and a half, really.
少校, 他们认为幽灵们50年之内不会再来
Major, they're not expecting
the Wraith for another fifty years.
我们必须让他们知道，这些幽灵随时都有可能出现
We have to let them know
they could show up at any time now.
如果你这么想，你干嘛不告诉他们
If you're so eager, why don't you tell them!
提醒你区域 51, 不是么?
Reminds you of Area 51, doesn't it?
大约 1918
Circa 1918.
我认为区域 51 不是在1918左右, 长官
I don't think Area 51 was around in 1918, sir.
- 嗯，是的
- 真的!
- Well, the area was.
- True!
我认为这些人们不可能拥有武器
I don't think there's a hope in hell
these people could have a weapon that...
各种大小不同，形状不同的武器, 少尉
Weapons come in all shapes and sizes, Lieutenant.
Sheppard少校, 我想你会发现这个的迷人之处
Major Sheppard, I think you'll find this intriguing.
好，我被骗了
OK, I'm intrigued.
这是什么?
What is it?
一种我们希望将来可以让我们对于幽灵们完全免疫的东西
Something that we hope will one day make
us completely immune to the Wraith.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第7集 完全中毒
Season 1 : Episode 7
Poisoning the well
根据 Druhin 长官的说法，这种药物仍然
According to Chancellor Druhin the drug is still
需要很长的时间才能研制完成
several years away from being finished.
我早说过了，根据现在的科技水平，那个，嗯,
I'd say, given their current level
of technology, that, er,
仍然处在理论阶段
could be an under-statement.
他们只是觉得他们已经很接近那个突破口了，但事实未必如此
Just because they believe they're close to
a breakthrough, it doesn't mean that they are.
你看到了，他们的整个的文明化的进程
You saw for yourself their entire civilisation is
是在那个目标完成的基础上的,  McKay博士
based upon the completion of that goal, Doctor McKay.
我不会低估他们的
I would not under estimate them.
我们可以确定幽灵是个很直接的威胁么?
Do we even know for certain that
the Wraith are an immediate threat?
我们可以打赌，他们不需要50年
We can probably bet they don't have fifty years.
后来Sheppard少校慷慨地向Hoffan人提供了帮助
Hence Major Sheppard has generously
offered our help to the Hoffans.
他有么?
Has he?
看,
Look,
实际上，如果他们已经差不多了,
the fact is, if they're onto something,
或者我们可以加快速度
maybe we can speed up the process.
好了, 少校, 走吧
OK, Major, you have a go.
但是，如果这个药只是个白日梦呢
But if the drug really is just a pipe dream...
我们的Beckett博士 已经自愿加入我们，半我们找到这个
Our Doctor Beckett's already volunteered
to help us find that out.
哦，他要加入，是么?
Oh, he has, huh?
他会的
He will.
我并不介意帮助他人
It's not that I mind lending people a hand...
- 不，当然不
-你是个大方的家伙，Carson
- No, of course not.
- You're a generous man, Carson.
但这是原则问题, 不是么?
but it's the principle of the thing, isn't it?
你不能在还没问过当事人之前，就帮人家做决定
You can't go volunteering someone
for something without consulting them first.
这不是自愿，不是么?
That's not even volunteering, is it?
这是强制
It's being pressed into service.
我不得不说，我不是
Not to mention the fact that I'm not...
军人，我不能命令你
not military, I can't give you orders.
我知道
I know.
不不不不不, 他只是不喜欢经过星际门
Nonononono, he just doesn't like
going through the Stargate.
他比McCoy博士还糟糕
He's worse than Doctor McCoy.
谁?
Who?
一个电视角色，就像Beckett博士在现实生活中的一样
The TV character that
Doctor Beckett plays in real life.
把人类的身体转化为能量
Converting a human body into energy
然后通过一个神经错乱的血窟窿将它传递数百万光年
and sending it millions of light years
through a wormhole bloody insanity.
C'mon,你多久去一次外星球?
C'mon, how often do you get
to travel to an alien planet?
我现在就在一个外星球上面!
I was already on an alien planet!
你干嘛把那些原料都混在一起?
Should you be messing with that stuff?
我知道自己在干嘛， 少校, 谢谢
I know what I'm doing, Major, thank you.
从这些东西的表面来看，他们已经掌握了最基本的生物化学，生理学,
From the looks of things they've mastered
a few basics biochemistry, physiology,
甚至还有一些分子生物学
perhaps even some form of molecular biology.
- 相当深刻的考虑
- 这是我们的先人的遗传
- Fairly impressive considering...
- It is our people's legacy.
这个房间展示了这数百年积累下来的医学知识
This room represents hundreds
of years of medical knowledge.
我是Perna, 这个项目的主管科研人员
I am Perna, chief scientist for the project.
John Sheppard
John Sheppard.
Uh, 这是 Teyla, 和Ford少尉
Uh, and this is Teyla, and Lieutenant Ford...
Carson
Carson.
Beckett
Beckett.
博士
Doctor.
我是说，叫我Carson就好
I mean, call me Carson.
我是，嗯， McKay博士, Rodney McKay博士
I'm, uh, Doctor McKay, Doctor Rodney McKay.
我希望我们的设备能帮到你
I hope you will find our facilities suitable.
哦，他们很棒!
Oh, they're charming!
非常棒!
Perfectly charming!
很久以前，这座城市只是对于我们想象的一个测试,
Long ago, this city was once
a testament to our imagination,
我们创造性的思维，会带来无止境的可能
our creative spirit, to endless possibility.
这是多久以前的事情了?
How long ago was that?
我们是被强迫的，这是真的
It is true that we have been forced
重建很多次，而且
to rebuild many times and
从来没有耗尽我们的潜能
never to our potential.
这就是为什么将这种药物完善如此重要
That is why perfecting the drug is so important.
这比将来仅仅依靠防御武器来对付幽灵重要得多
It is more than just a defence
against the Wraith it is our future.
尊敬的说一句, 长官,你是无法阻止优胜劣汰的，这是生存的基本事实
With respect, Chancellor, you cannot
prevent the culling it is a fact of existence.
我们正在挑战的一个事实
A fact we challenge.
我们总是在寻找终止恶性循环的方法
We will always search for a way
to end the cycle of destruction.
幽灵族总是会阻止其他其他发展比较快的种族
The Wraith will always prevent
any race from advancing too far.
你认为你能打败他们?
You figure you can beat 'em?
是的，通过这些知识
Yes, through knowledge.
有很多就像这个一样的成果被隐藏在这个城市的各个角落
A number of archives like this one
are hidden throughout the city.
只有很少的人知道
Their existence is known only to a few.
这是
This is...
非常的
very...
令人印象深刻
impressive.
我们特别保存了每一代人留下的成果
We meticulously preserve
the accomplishments of each generation
在他们被幽灵们毁了之前
before they are wiped out by the Wraith.
所以你们所学的东西都是在这儿?
So everything your people ever learned is in here?
还有其他和这个一样的成就
And in other archives identical to this one.
万一他们毁了一个
In case they destroy one.
你们认真点
You guys are serious about this.
站在先人的肩膀上
Standing on the shoulders of our forefathers.
你对这种药研究了多长时间?
How long have you been working on this Wraith drug?
150年前,
One hundred and fifty years ago,
我们的科学家几乎就要成功的研制这种新药,
our scientists were close to
creating a viable prototype,
可是还没看到结果却过世了
only to die before seeing its fruition.
所以你希望,如果这个世界对他们来说不再美好,
So you're hoping that, if this world's no good to them,
他们就搬走?
they're just gonna move on?
幽灵不会把我们当作是种威胁的
The Wraith cannot possibly perceive us as a threat.
你知道么，老实告诉你吧，我不知道他们会有什么反应
Y'know, to tell you the truth,
I don't know how they would react.
如果他们选择将你们除去，那你会一点办法都没有
If they choose to wipe you
out of existence, you will be helpless.
我们不能寄希望于控制他们的行动
We cannot hope to control their actions.
我们做我们能做的
We can only do what we can
就是结束这个进行了太久的循环
to end the cycle that has gone on for far too long.
他的名字是Ferrel Mylan
His name was Ferrel Mylan.
在他在上次优胜劣汰中死去之前,
Before he died in the last culling,
他是我们这里最有名的医学研究者之一
he was one of our most celebrated medical researchers.
他是创建者之一
He was the one who found it.
创建什么?
Found what?
钥匙
The key.
他的日记，告诉我们一个男人如何在一次和幽灵的相遇中存活下来
His journals tell of one man who
survived an encounter with the Wraith.
Ferrel Mylan的小组发现这个男人拥有一种特殊的蛋白质,
Ferrel Mylan's team discovered that
this man possessed a unique protein,
一种可以抵抗幽灵释放的化学药物的物质
one that enabled him to resist the
chemical released by the Wraith
可以帮助他们的受害人将毒物排出
to precipitate draining of life from their victims
在反复试验之后
After painstaking trial and error...
Ferrel 制成了蛋白质的翻版
Ferrel made a copy of the protein.
他最后终于可以制成这个药物的原型
He was eventually able to create a prototype of a drug
可以用来扰乱幽灵的膳食
designed to interfere with the Wraith feeding process.
有用么?
And it worked?
Ferrel在这种药物可以用来保护Hoff前被杀了
Ferrel was killed before
the drug could be used to defend Hoff.
现在这成了你的工作
And it's been your job
要证明他的努力不是白费的
to make certain his work wasn't in vain.
很大的责任
Quite the responsibility.
是很荣幸的
It is a great honour.
你如何确信
Ferrel 没有粉饰他的成果,
How do you know for certain that this
Ferrel wasn't just embellishing his results,
或者这只是虚构的?
or for that matter making them up?
我的意思是，你所能利用的只有他的笔记
I mean, all you have to go on are his notes.
他和他的伙伴一直工作到最后一刻
He and his team worked until the last possible moment.
他们知道 Wraith的舰队就在头顶上
They knew the Wraith ships were overhead
但仍然在晚上头头的工作,
and still they worked through the night,
希望能找到更有力的发现,
hoping to provide one more insight,
不是为了他们自己
one last thread of knowledge not for themselves
而是为了下一代
but for the generation that would survive.
为了能为他们创造这一点点宝贵的时间，成千上万的士兵们牺牲了性命
Ten thousand soldiers gave their lives
to give them those last few hours.
Ferrel's 日记上的最后一句话，所有Hoffans人都知道
The last words of Ferrel's journal
are known to all Hoffans.
我不是冒犯, Perna
I meant no disrespect, Perna.
没关系
It's alright.
在那时候，不止是他的日记留下了
More than just his journals survived the culling.
他的研究材料也被保存得很好,
His research materials were safeguarded as well,
包括细心保存的幽灵细胞的样本
including carefully preserved Wraith cell samples
我们现在仍然可以利用
which we still use in our work today.
请
Please.
你自己看
See for yourself.
哦!
Oh!
简直是难以置信!
That's incredible!
我亲眼看到了, Weir博士
I saw it with my own eyes, Doctor Weir.
是的，在这个培养皿里,
Yes, in a Petri dish,
我们谈论的是150多年前的幽灵的细胞
and we are talking about
a hundred and fifty year old Wraith cells.
我的意思是，他们现在对这些药物已经免疫了,
I mean, for all we know, they could be immune to
the drug by now,
或者找别的东西对付它
or come up with defences against it.
嗯，我不这么想，博士
Well, I don't think so, Doctor.
我使用了一点研究人员的特权
I took the liberty of running a few tests of my own
使用了一些
using cells taken
Sheppard少校从Athos带回的幽灵的胳膊上个的细胞
from the Wraith arm
Major Sheppard brought back from Athos.
结果还是一样
The results were the same...
几乎可以完全抵抗
near complete resistance.
这其中肯定有点什么
They've definitely got something.
相信我，我比任何人都觉得惊讶
Believe me, I'm more surprised than anyone.
所以你的建议是?
So what do you recommend?
我们将他们的工作推向另一个水准
That we take their work to the next level.
我已经通知了 Hoffans ，我们有客人
I've informed the Hoffans of our guest in the brig.
你知道你在说什么么?
You realise what you're asking for?
我知道
I do.
有什么新情况,军士?
Anything I should know about, Sergeant?
没有，长官，他很安静
No, sir, he's been quiet.
还在试图让你看到什么?
Still trying to make you see things?
他已经放弃了
He's given up on that.
我觉得他坚持不了多久
I didn't think he'd last this long.
又见面了, Sheppard少校
Hello again, Major Sheppard.
很抱歉，如果我打搅了你
Sorry if I woke you.
只是过来看看你有什么需要
Just came by to see if there's anything you needed.
杂志，干净的毛巾
Magazine, fresh towels.
你没有很好的掩饰你的恐惧, 少校
You hide your fear poorly, Major.
你知道的，我们像这样谈话已经好几个星期了,
Y'know, we've been having these conversations
for a couple of weeks now,
但我还不知道你的名字
and I don't even know your name.
你们也有名字，对吧?
You guys do have names, right?
让我猜猜
Let me guess...
Steve?
我是你的死神
I am your death.
你只要知道这个就够了
That is all you need to know.
我更喜欢Steve
I prefer Steve.
你想要什么?
What do you hope to gain from this?
我只是想更加了解你们一些，打破我们之间的隔阂
Just trying to bridge the gap between
our two cultures; get to know you better.
试试看如何让你变温和一些
That and try to figure out how to keep your kind
从上百万无辜的人那里获得生命
from sucking the life
out of millions of innocent people.
就算我告诉你那些你想知道的东西,
Even if I told you what you want to know,
也不会改变什么
it would change nothing.
你的命运和那些阻碍我们的人类一样
You are doomed as are any humans that stand in our way.
没有更好的死法了么?
Can't be a nice way to die?
饥饿,
Hungry,
慢慢的,
slow,
你的食物
knowing your food source is just...
看得见摸不着
out of reach.
为什么把我关在这里?
Why do you keep me here?
我要知道我们将要面临的是什么
I need to know what we're up against.
比如说,
For example,
你们到底有多少这种大的飞船，它们在哪里?
how many of those big hive ships
have you got and where are they?
告诉你有什么好处
You have nothing to offer me in return.
或许我们会给你吃的
We could talk about easing your hunger...
Steve
Steve.
你不会牺牲你的同类的
You would never sacrifice one of your own kind.
它们就站在
And yet, it is all that stands between
你和你找寻的那些信息之间
you and the information you seek.
现在我们唯一的资源就是活的幽灵细胞
Using living Wraith cells
is our only recourse at this juncture.
否则我们无法确信这种药物是否有用
Without them we have no way of knowing
for certain if the drug is actually viable.
你说过它
You said it worked effectively on the cells
对我们带回来的那只幽灵胳膊上的细胞是很有效的
of the severed Wraith arm we brought back.
的确如此
It did.
但是它有很多地方已经腐烂了
But those were already in a partially decayed state.
我们需要活的样品
We need live samples.
如果有新的样品
And with new samples
你就可以研制出药物原型?
you think it's possible to create a prototype?
只要有足够的时间，我就可以
Given enough time, yes I do.
他已经突破了困扰 Hoffans的地方了
He's got a good point
the Hoffans are practically obsessed.
谢谢, Rodney
Thank you, Rodney.
我同意, 博士
I agree, Doctor.
但是那对于他们来说或许没什么
But their obsession may become their undoing.
嗯，不管怎样，对我们总有好处
Well, even if they do... undo, it'd be good for us.
我的意思是，如果有机会，难道你不想注射这样的疫苗么?
I mean, given the choice, wouldn't you want to be immune?
否则就要成为幽灵的食物
Not if it meant the lives
the Wraith might otherwise spare.
除非每一个人，每一个角落都有这样的免疫力,
This drug would only be of value if everyone,
这药才是真正有用的
everywhere, possessed the same immunity.
这个想法倒是不错
There's a thought worth pursuing.
我同意
I agree.
少校,跟你的犯人有什么新的进展了么?
Major, have you made any progress with your prisoner?
没有，他眨了下眼睛
Well, not yet, but he just blinked.
眨眼?
He blinked?
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
说明他仍然有把握
It means he's still holding on
他好像暗示说他很快就可以出去了
but he's indicated to me that he may break soon.
他告诉你这个，然后
And he indicated this to you by...
眨眼?
blinking?
是的
Yes.
没有攻击, 少校,
但是到目前为止，他什么也没告诉你
No offence, Major,
but so far he hasn't told you a thing.
他只是在拖延
For all we know he could linger
拖几个月，然后
this way for months and ultimately
我们仍然什么都不知道
we'll learn nothing.
当我们说话的时候，幽灵们可能已经向着Hoff来了
The Wraith could be on their way to Hoff as we speak.
如果你的犯人对于新药的研制有关键作用,
If your prisoner holds the key
to the creation of this drug,
should we not take advantage of this?
我们怎样才能安全的从他身上取得样本呢?
How can we get the sample off him safely?
我们仍然有当时抓住他的武器
We still possess the weapons used in his capture.
让他再次束手就擒是件容易的事情
It would be a simple matter of incapacitating him again.
所以，这是可能的?
So, then, it's possible?
当然可能
It's possible.
嗨, Steve
Hi, Steve.
再见, Steve
Bye, Steve.
博士
Doctor.
他
Is he...
我是说，你确定他
I mean, you're certain he's...
他已经昏过去了, 博士
He's down, Doc.
做你想做的事情吧
Do your thing.
看起来很无害，不是么?
Almost looks peaceful, doesn't he?
无害?!
Peaceful?!
你简直是昏头了!
You're out of your bloody mind!
我重来没见过这样的设备!
I have never seen devices such as these!
你的工作正在做最后的提炼
The work you've done refining
这种药物应该很快就好了
the drug has been good up til now.
有了这个我们能做得更好
With all this we can make it better.
我觉得,
From what I can tell,
你现在最关键的是接种的测试
your biggest problem is that the test inoculations
现在还不能证实
failed to show enough of a presence
这对人体是有效的
in human cells to be effective.
我们需要的是一个更好的传输系统
What we need is a better delivery system.
正是
Exactly.
现在最好是先别管那些关键的蛋白质
And the best place to start
is to recreate the key protein
来看看血清吧
in the serum and work our way up from there.
如果我们可以避免
If we can avoid having
它的自我重造,
to re-engineer it from a natural source,
制成一个完全人工的版本,
and make an entirely synthetic version,
这样它的有效性将大大提升
it should ultimately increase the efficiency.
这可能么?
Such a thing is possible?
只要你愿意努力试试，没什么不可能
Anything's possible if you're willing to give it a go.
那还说什么，赶紧开始吧
C'mon then, a bald head is soon shaved.
你和其他人的口音有点不同
You speak differently than the others.
发现了么?!
Noticed that, did you?!
很抱歉如果我把你弄迷糊了
Sorry if I confuse you.
相信我，我的家乡,
这起了很大的作用
Trust me, where I come from,
it all makes perfect sense.
那里什么样子?
What is it like?
苏格兰？哦，那里很美
Scotland? Oh, I think it's beautiful.
但我听说这是一种嗜好
But I'm told it's something of an acquired taste.
我是说你的世界
I meant your world.
那儿一定很和平,
It must be so peaceful there,
因为幽灵不会去
knowing that the Wraith will not come.
哦，你一定很惊讶，那里一点也不和平
Oh, you'd be surprised how not peaceful it is.
人们都很堕落
We're spoiled rotten, now that I think of it.
你错过了
You miss it.
对不起，让你难过了
I'm sorry for enquiring.
哦，没关系，没关系，亲爱的
Oh, no, no. Don't be, love.
Perna!
所有细胞都渗透了．
One hundred percent cellular penetration
在所有的5次接种测试里
in all five test inoculations.
简直是难以置信啊!
Incredible!
仍然还有很多数据需要分析
There's still a lot of data to be analysed
不过我相信，这个最初的结果是很棒的
but the initial results are very promising, I agree.
Beckett 的努力让这个项目加快发展
Doctor Beckett's efforts
have advanced the project by decades.
Perna的那些公式正在运作着
Perna's formula was right on track.
这是改变了它的分子构成
It was just a matter of changing its molecular design
这样的话，更加便于身体的吸收
so it could be better absorbed by the body.
博士，这对于人民们来说是个巨大的胜利
This is an enormous victory for our people, Doctor.
我不知道该如何感谢你
I don't know how to thank you.
不需要
No need.
当然，这只是初步阶段
Of course, it's only a preliminary.
你什么时候可以开始下一步测试?
How soon until you can set up the next stage of testing?
今天晚点时候我会把进程给您，长官
You'll have a schedule later today, Chancellor.
抱歉，下一步?
I'm sorry next stage?
你的报告已经说得很清楚了
Your report makes it abundantly clear that
这个项目正准备进行下一个阶段
the project is ready to proceed to its next phase.
我们想用你的犯人测试一下血清的有效性
We want to test the serum's
effectiveness against your prisoner.
你赞成?
And you support this?
嗯，我知道他肯定是要死的
Well, I know for certain he's gonna die
所以或许我们应该好好利用他
so we might as well make good use of him
当他还活着的时候
while he's still alive.
你真的了解日内瓦协定
You do understand the Geneva Convention
禁止用犯人做科学试验?
prohibits using prisoners for scientific experiments?
没有关系，博士，幽灵又没有
No offence, Doc, but had the Wraith
加入日内瓦协定,
attended the Geneva Convention,
他们可能会把这的每一个人都给吃了
they would have tried to feed on everyone there.
Beckett的报告显示，我们还无法确定
Beckett's report indicates that we have no idea
这种药对于人的长期效用
what the long-term effect
of this drug on humans might be.
但是，我们很清楚
Well, we know damn well what
要是幽灵入侵了，我们会怎样，不是么?
the long-term effects of Wraith culling are, don't we?
我们在说的是把一个活人
We're talking about putting a human being
和一个饿得要死的幽灵放在一个房间里
in the same room as a starving Wraith.
一旦我们开始前进
Now once we start down that road...
你觉得我们该怎么走哪条?
Which road did you think we were headed down?
不是这条
Not this one.
至少不是这么快
At least not this fast.
花时间在犯人身上，我不同情他
Having spent time with the prisoner, I don't pity him.
无论如何，他都是要死的
He's gonna die anyway.
这种药将来或许会很有用
This drug could be useful some day.
将来
Some day.
关键是，这样的机会不多
The point is, we don't get
a lot of opportunities like this.
你知道
Do you know how obsessed with this the Hoffans are
当HOFFENS知道我们抓了一个幽灵时有多迷惑?
when they found out we had a live Wraith prisoner?
他反正时要死的
He's going to die.
我们试着给他吃各种各样活的东西
I've tried to feed him all sorts of life stuff
但是看起来他只吃一样
but apparently there's only one item on his menu.
测试人是谁?
What about the test subject?
如果失败了
If the drug fails...
我们不是从大街上随便抓一个人来
We're not just grabbing anybody off the street.
这个人得了绝症，晚期了
The test subject is a terminally ill
他自愿的
patient who has volunteered himself.
这不是一个决定
These are not exactly the type of decisions
我想试试
I was expecting to make on this expedition.
做吧
Do it.
嗨, Steve
Hi, Steve.
还要样本?
More samples?
我想沿着一片田地
I was thinking more along the lines of a field trip.
你想要食物么?
You want sustenance?
我要信息
I want information.
你无法提供这样的交易
You are incapable of offering such a trade.
如果你告诉我一些有价值的东西，我给你吃的
You tell me something of value, I let you eat.
这就是你的晚餐
That's the deal.
要或不要
Take it or leave it.
很好
Very well.
他们准备好了么?
Are they ready?
Sheppard少校和Ford少尉
正将犯人送去探险者2号
Major Sheppard and Lieutenant Ford
are loading the prisoner into Jumper Two.
bates军士也准备好了
Sergeant bates is already on the ground
在集合地点等待他们的降落
and standing by for their arrival
at the rendezvous site.
探险者2号, 我是Weir
Jumper Two, this is Weir.
你现在怎样?
What's your status?
很好
Nice and cosy in here.
准备出发
We're ready to depart.
注意安全 少校
Be safe, Major.
这就是计划
That's the plan.
探险者2号，准备发射
Jumper Two, you are go for launch.
Roger
Roger that.
拉起来
Dial it up.
嗨，伙计，这并不有趣
Hey, man, this isn't supposed to be fun.
Perna 跟我说了你的病情
Perna explained to me about your illness.
我希望你知道我很抱歉
I want you to know how sorry I am.
我希望可以帮你做点什么
I wish there was something I could do for you.
时间到了, Beckett博士
It's my time, Doctor Beckett.
现在看我的运气吧
I'm at peace with my fate.
我希望你知道，这很重要，
I think it's important you know
或许结果没有想得那么好
that we may be talking about a
less than peaceful ending here.
我已经跟 Merell 详细的解释过会发生什么事情
I have explained to Merell in
great detail what may befall him.
你必须明白这种药物重来没有使用过
You should also understand
that this drug has never worked
除了在实验室不断的模拟试验
in anything other than a laboratory simulation.
我们无法确定会发生什么事情
We don't know for certain what will happen.
就算没有用,
Even if it doesn't work,
你也可以知道一些有价值的信息
you'll learn something of value
将来如何完善它?
how to perfect it in the future?
或许，但你没有理由去面对那些生物
Possibly, but that's no reason
for you to face that creature.
Beckett博士, 我不害怕
Doctor Beckett, I'm not afraid.
不管发生什么事情，我的死都会很有意义
No matter what happens, my death will have meaning.
这不就是我们努力争取的么,
Is that not something we all strive for,
死得有意义?
to die knowing we made a difference?
我想这么做
I want to do this.
请不要让我失去这个为人民服务的机会
Please don't deny me the chance to help my people.
你怎么看?
What do you think?
我实在无法相信
That it goes against everything I believe in.
在我的家乡，学医的人之中流传一种诅咒
There's an oath among medical people where I come from.
刚开始，并没有什么害处
It begins, First, do no harm.
- 对你很重要的话
- 不止这些Perna
- Important words to you.
- More than words, Perna.
试验就要开始了
The battle rages at the very
threshold of our laboratory now.
我们努力工作到最好，知道
Those of us working to the last know
这最后的一点时间是很宝贵的,
that these few final hours have been dearly purchased,
我们的注意力还没有消减
yet our concentration has not waned.
我们无法期望自救
We cannot hope to save ourselves
但是我们可以希望最后一点有力的发现,
but we can hope that one last insight,
在我们还剩最后一口气之前,
one last revelation before we take our dying breaths,
可能可以阻止这样恐怖的事情再次发生
may prevent this terrible day from happening again.
Ferrel的最后一次日记
Ferrel's last journal entry.
什么都别说, Carson
More than words, Carson.
我明白
I understand that.
我了解
I do.
但是还有很多人不知道
But there are too many unknowns.
我们需要时间来确定它的副作用
We need time to determine the possible side-effects...
没有时间了!
There is no time!
你这么害怕犯错么
Are you so afraid of making a mistake
那你永远也无法知道我们要面临的是什么?
that you can no longer see what we're up against?
不是害怕犯错 Perna,
This isn't about making mistakes Perna,
这是方法问题,
it's about the end justifying the means,
对于我们的专业而言，这是个灾难
and in our profession that's a very slippery slope.
我们并不确定这一定有效
We have no idea if this'll work.
我们可能是将这个人送给了一个怪物
We could be sacrificing that man to a monster.
还会有其他人接替他的位置
There will be another to take his place.
这就是我害怕的
That's just what I'm afraid of.
他们好了
They are ready.
当心
Careful, sir.
这就是你承诺的食物?
This is the sustenance you promised?
计划有点变动
Little change in plans.
你现在就告诉我，否则就什么都没有了
You tell me something right now,
or the damned party's cancelled.
你想知道什么?
What do you want to know?
还有多少舰队
How many hive ships have become operational
自从我们唤醒了第一个?
since we awakened the first one?
所有, Sheppard少校
All of them, Major Sheppard.
首先，他们会去饲养基地，增强力量
First, they will travel to their own
feeding grounds and gather strength.
我们是很有忍耐力的民族, 少校
We are a patient race, Major.
当我们的力量完全聚集之后,
When we have taken our fill and gathered our strength,
就会向你们发起攻击
we will join force and come for you.
什么时候?
D'you have any idea when that'll be?
早上?
Morning?
下午?
Afternoon?
打开
Open it up.
你不需要这么做
You don't have to do this.
我知道
I know.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
他很虚弱
He is weak.
你们都是Hoffan人民的英雄
You are both heroes of the Hoffan people.
我承认，这很疯狂
I'll admit, it was amazing.
我希望你的朋友也能加入我们
I hope your friends will join us for
的一个为你办的庆功宴
a celebratory banquet to honour your work.
我们很愿意参加，但是你
We'll be glad to attend, but don't you
觉不觉得庆功宴有点太早了?
think celebrations are a bit premature?
这个结果
The results speak for themselves.
我打算让议会通过
I intend to ask the Council to approve
大批量生产这种血清,立即生效
mass production of the serum, effective immediately.
今天之后,
我想不会有任何异议
After what happened today,
I doubt they will offer any resistance.
这真是个好消息，长官
That is wonderful news, Chancellor.
值得尊重，不
With all due respect, no it isn't.
我们现在在说的是一个测试
We're talking about one test here.
对于这个结果我和大家一样高兴
Now I'm as pleased as anyone with the results
但是我们还要很多事情要做
but we still have a lot of work to do
在我们开始将它投入生产之前
before we can start using it.
Beckett 博士希望可以进行一系列测试
Doctor Beckett wishes to run a full series of tests
对这个结果进行反覆论证
on Merell prior to issuing his final report.
可能会有些副作用
There may have been mitigating circumstances
比如说，这个人可能会死
the man was dying, for one.
当然
Of course.
我会跟议会说明的
I'll bring it up with Council.
为了成功
To success.
怎么了?
What is it?
Steve看起来好像很难受
It's Steve he doesn't look so good.
他这个样子多久了?
How long has he been like this?
测试之后
Since the test.
是不是什么诡计?
Think it's a ruse?
他们不会来这套
It is not their way.
嗨
Hey.
你对我做了什么?
What have you done to me?
叫Beckett过来
We need Beckett in here.
快去
Go.
我们会帮你的
We're gonna help you.
不需要你的可怜
Don't feel pity for me.
其他幽灵来的时候，你们会比我现在更惨
You will suffer far worse when the others come for you.
少校
Major.
我正准备把他解剖
I was just about to cut him open.
那我先走
Then, I was just leaving.
我已经做了一系列的测试，你可能对结果会有兴趣
I've already done a series of tests
you might like to know the results of.
你知道是什么使他死去的么?
You know what killed him?
我检查了他身体的一部分，发现，
I'm gonna go out on a limb here and say
他体内的重要器官几乎同时停止工作
that it was all of his vital organs
shutting down almost simultaneously.
他是饿死的么?
Did he starve to death?
不
No.
取决于他的体制,
Based on the condition his body's in,
我觉得他不是饿死的
I don't think he died from a lack of nourishment.
那么是什么?
Well, then, what was it?
初步测试显示
Initial tests revealed a significant amount
在他体内有相当数量的HOFFEN的血清
of Hoffan serum in his bloodstream.
我想在他身体的
I'm guessing we'll find similar trace amounts
的其他部分也一样，如果我们一一测试的话
in each of his organs once we analyse those as well.
为什么这种药物会是他的血液凝固?
Why did the Hoffan drug end up in his blood?
根据Hoffans的研究,
From the Hoffans' research,
我们知道当幽灵吃东西时,
we know that when the Wraith feed,
他们会向食物体内注射一种化学物质
they release a chemical into their victims' bodies.
但是我们还不清楚这种物质到底起什么作用,
What it actually does, we don't yet understand,
我猜测，在某种程度上，
but I can only assume that it prepares the human body
可以使人体慢慢干枯
in some way to be drained of life.
这种血清本来是
The serum is designed
用来抵御这种物质的，当它一进入人体时，使之冻结
to shield the victim from that
initial chemical release, blocking it.
好的
OK.
我猜测这种血清蛋白产生了变异
I think the serum protein may have mutated
当它和幽灵释放的化学物质相遇时,
when it was exposed to the Wraith chemical,
触发了某些中毒的反应
triggering some sort of toxic reaction.
所以不但没有吃掉他
So instead of feeding off of him...
自己反而死了
... he was poisoned.
如果血清真是这样,
So if the serum did this,
那么这不仅仅是种地狱幽灵的药物
then it's more than just a defence against the Wraith.
甚至可以杀死他们
It kills 'em.
我不知道为什么拉警报, 少校
I fail to see cause for alarm, Major.
这个发现大大增强了血清的价值
If anything, this development dramatically
increases the value of the serum.
现在没有任何疑问 了
No it just takes away any doubt
当幽灵们最终到这里的时候要干什么
about what the Wraith'll do
when they eventually come here.
我不觉得有什么不同
I fail to see the difference.
一旦他们知道我们拥有这样一种武器,
Once they learn you possess a weapon such as this,
幽灵们会为了死去的幽灵报仇而将我们灭族
the Wraith will wipe your people from
existence in retaliation for the Wraith deaths.
或者他们会把我们留下，当他们发现我们
Or they may simply leave us
alone once they learn we are...
一点都不好吃
unpalatable.
因为他们是种随和的，愿意和别人和平共处的族类
Cos they're such an easy-going
live-and-let-live kind of race.
你知道的，或许有一半的机会
Y'know, maybe there was half a chance
当你谈论
of that when you were talking
这个的时候,但是现在
about this being defensive, but now...
你无法看到更多了, 少校
You fail to see the larger picture, Major.
一开始，我们本可以不尽是防卫
For the first time we have a way to not
还要反攻
just defend ourselves but to strike back.
这到底是报复呢，还是保卫你的人民?
Is this about revenge, or saving your people?
你无法理解这样的痛苦
You can't hope to understand
the generations of suffering...
我在他们那里待过，跟他们战斗过,
I've been in one of their hives and
I've fought against their ships and,
相信我，一旦有一个幽灵因为这种药物而死了,
trust me, when the first Wraith
dies because of this drug,
他们不会轻易就离开的
they're not gonna simply move on.
他们会把这个问题解决
They're gonna make their problem go away.
一旦你的世界被毁了,
Once your world has been destroyed,
他们会找出任何一个和你有关联的人
they will seek out any who have had contact with you.
他们不会放过任何一个
They will spare no-one.
听着，我知道你对这个抱着很大的热情
Listen, I know how passionate you are about this
这药或许从某种意义上来说像圣杯一样, 但是
this drug is sort of your Holy Grail, but...
在我们想出更好的办法之前，这个最后暂时停停
You're gonna have to shelve it
till we get a better idea...
不，不
No, no.
我是认真的，否则我们无法再帮助你们了
I'm serious otherwise we can't help you any more.
你不明白, 少校, 太晚了e
You don't understand, Major, it's too late.
我已经向以后提案并通过了
I have made my recommendation
to the Council and they've agreed.
我们已经在给我们的人民接种
We have already begun inoculating our people.
你要走么?
You are leaving?
除非你愿意回复正常的工作
Unless you're willing to go back to formal work
对于血清，我没有任何的立足点，不是么?
on the serum there's no point my staying, is there?
- Carson
- Perna, 你必须再次开始这个项目
- Perna, you need to re-open the project.
要做更多的工作,
With more work,
或许你可以阻止这样的突变
maybe you could prevent the mutation
使它仅仅成为一种抵抗性药物
maintain it as a defensive drug only.
Merell 死了
Merell is dead.
他们今天早上发现的
They found him this morning.
死因至今不明
The cause of death is still to be determined.
现在还有时间让他们停止接种这种药物
There's still time they need to stop the inoculations.
- 他们不会的
- 有人已经死了
- They won't.
- A man is dead.
但这并不意味着其他人也会一样
Which doesn't necessarily mean more will follow.
如果没有更多的证据，就算我想，也无法阻止他们
Even if I wanted to, I couldn't make
them stop, not without more proof.
Perna ，你是我见过的最聪明的人
Perna you're one of the brightest people I've ever met.
为了你自己，我求你,
For your own sake, I beg you,
不要在参与进来了,
have no more part in this,
除非我们有了更多的新发现
at least  until we know more.
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
为什么?
Why not?
因为我也是第一批接种的人之一
Because I was among the first to be inoculated.
我佩服你的危机意识,博士,
I appreciate your sense of urgency, Doctor,
但是现在就匆匆下结论是很不明智的
but at this point it would be
unwise to rush to any conclusions.
现在你要练习谨慎么?
Now you wanna exercise caution?
你是认真的?!
Are you serious?!
少校,你自己也说幽灵们可能就要来了
Major, you yourself have told us the Wraith
could be on their way here right now.
除了前进我们别无选择
We have no choice but to move forward.
长官，你是代表大多数人说话的
You're speaking on behalf
of a lot of people, Chancellor.
你觉得我会强迫我的人民接受这个?
You think I would force this choice upon my own people?
不，先生，我的人民们完全同意
No, sir, our people are in complete agreement.
在幽灵们还没来之前，他们可能就会死
Your people may be dead before the Wraith
even get here for all you know.
长官，求您，现在还不晚
Chancellor, please, it's not too late.
至少推迟接种，在我们知道Merell的死因之前
Suspend the inoculations at least
until we know what killed Merell.
他本来就是末期了
He was terminal.
我们还不确定这种血清是促成他死亡的因素之一
We don't know for certain
the serum played any part in his death.
他突然停止呼吸
He suffered a sudden and
complete respiratory breakdown.
可能是他本身的病所致
Which could well have been due to his condition.
他的病已经扩散到全身了
His sickness had spread through most of his body.
难道你想用成千上万人民的生命来冒险
Are you willing to risk thousands of people's lives
在这个假设的基础上,因为我不是!
based on that assumption, because I'm not!
Sheppard少校?
Major Sheppard?
说, Teyla
Go ahead, Teyla.
我们在医疗中心
We're in the medical centre.
现在需要帮助
We need help.
上帝!
My God!
Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard.
医生说从作文开始就有这样的病人陆续到来,
The doctors say they began arriving last night,
他们的数量每小时都在不断增长
and their numbers have been increasing by the hour.
少校
Major.
我在听，继续
I'm on it go.
少尉, 呼叫Weir, 告诉他我们要...
Lieutenant, radio Weir, tell 'em we need
一只设备齐全的医疗队
a full medical support team
on a Jumper and inbound ASAP.
我需要帮助!
I need help here!
氧气!
Oxygen!
放轻松
Take it easy.
别管我们
Leave us.
你对那里发生的事情有什么看法?
D'you have any idea what's going on out there?
我知道, 少校
I do, Major.
有一半的接种了那种药物的人死了
Half the people you gave that drug to are dying.
一半, 少校, 一半
Half of them, Major, half.
这个几率很明显
The statistics are clear
已经确定了，就是这个概率,
and the numbers are holding at
that level, it's just been confirmed,
这就意味着剩下的一半人将活着,
which means the other fifty percen
of those we inoculated will live,
会杀了任何想把他们当食物的幽灵
and destroy any Wraith who try to feed on them.
简直无法相信!
I don't believe this!
现在幽灵们会知道Hoffan人民的全罪
Now the Wraith will know the full
conviction of the Hoffan people.
罪行?!
Conviction?!
你到底明不明白，如果
Do you realise that if we could spread
如果我们向银河的每一个人发放这种药物,
this drug to every human in the galaxy,
以后的人永远都不会知道
future generations would never
知道这种优胜劣汰的恐怖
know the horror of a culling.
你故意牺牲上百万的生命
You're deliberately sacrificing millions of lives.
这是幽灵们的终结!
An end to the Wraith!
你为什么非要这么理解?
You can't comprehend the bargain in that?
我们不能这么做!
You can't make a bargain lik
that for your entire people!
你觉得是我一意孤行么?
Do you think I'm alone in this conviction?
我想这是你的错觉!
I think you're delusional!
你会看到的
You shall see.
我们是投票表决的
We are putting it to a vote as we speak.
我代表大多数人的意见
I will stand by the decision of the majority.
这样你满意了么?
Does that satisfy you?
他们明白自己在表决什么么?
Do they have any idea what they're voting on?
是的
Yes.
我保证
I promise you.
如果大部分人都不赞同，那么你会停止?
And you'll back off if it doesn't go your way?
是的
You have my word.
这些房间你随便用吧
Use whatever rooms you need for overflow.
我们要保持这片地方的干净
We need to keep this area clear for triage.
Teyla, 你在这
Teyla, there you are.
请确认氧气瓶在医院的各处都分配好了
Make sure that our oxygen is properly
deployed throughout the hospital.
博士
Doctor.
让那些不是很严重的病人先轮流用
Have non-critical patients use it in turns
保持呼吸平稳
just long enough to stabilise their breathing.
Teyla, 你在这儿干嘛?
Teyla, what are you doing here?
你没听到我说什么么
You're not listening to me.
Perna呢?
我需要她的帮忙
Now where's Perna?
I need her here.
Carson
Carson.
我想再看看Atlantis
I would... like to have seen Atlantis.
Perna
Perna.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
别这样
Don't be.
对于我所做的我很平静,
I am at peace with what
I have done,
你也应该这样
as you should be.
我希望我从来没参与过这件事情
I wish I'd had no part in this.
你带给我们希望
You gave us hope.
很多年了，我们一直在努力研究
For... years, our people have been working...
向着这个目标
towards this...
每分每秒
very moment.
我们没有背叛我们的祖先
We didn't betray the forefathers.
我们完成了他们的使命
We have fulfilled their destiny, their promise.
是
Aye.
停下
Stay.
- 你还好吧?
- 是
- You OK?
- Aye.
听说你要走了
I am told you are leaving.
是的
Yes, we are.
不是那个
Not that it hasn't been... lovely.
我希望你离开前看看投票的结果
I wanted you to see the results
of the vote before you left.
96％的人赞成
Ninety-six percent in favour.
是全民投票么?
Does the vote include all your people?
每个人
Every one.
你看到了, 少校,我们都很一致，大家都很坚决
So you see, Major, we speak with one voice,
and we are resolute.
是的
Yeah.
我明白了
I can see that.
下次我们见面的时候，我希望可以讨论比较好的办法
When next we meet, I would like to discuss the best way
尽可能的把药分到世界的各个角落
to disseminate the drug on as many worlds as possible.
我们不会很快久这么做的
We won't be doing that any time soon.
或许我们的胜利会让你改变主意
Perhaps our victory will change your mind.
但我们回来的时候，我不认为你还会在
If and when we ever return,
I don't imagine you'll be here.
我也不认为还会有任何人的存在
I don't imagine anybody else will be, either.
好运
Good luck.
"不计任何代价的胜利"
"Victory at all costs".
听起来很耳熟, 少校?
That sound familiar, Major?
Churchill
Churchill.
是
Aye.
我决不会同意的
Never thought I'd disagree.